Jinyoung Jeong

Frontend Developer

+353 083 137 0599 jinyoung.jeong20@gmail.com 163 Bettyglen, Raheny, Dublin 5, Ireland

www.thisis-jin.com github.com/jinnn0

About Me

I'm a self-taught Frontend developer who found a passion for building web applications. I was introduced to programming when I was trying to figure out **how** and **why** certain websites are just **different**. I was fascinated by clean UI designs and effective, interactive functionalities that I experienced on web that it eventually led myself to learn the skills to build on my own. Ever since I wrote the first line of code, I am continuously learning to become a better developer. I care about writing better code, gaining the right knowledges I need to build the product, user experience and more.

Skills & Tools

HTML, CSS / SCSS, JavaScript / ES6, React, Redux, Styled Components, GSAP, Canvas, Webpack, Git, GitHub

Projects

To Do

A todo app with 4 different views (Focus, Daily, Weekly, Monthly). Core things I learnt were React router, Context API, Form submit, Date object, Event bubbling, Scrolling event and dealing with complex component tree & css

React, Context API, GSAP

Timer

Minimalistic timer application that I built to actually use for my study time. The app can switch between timer or stopwatch view on the fly. It incorporates dark mode toggle. I learnt a lot about Object-oriented JavaScript.

HTML, CSS, Vanila JS

Twitter Clone

Full stack Twitter clone app. It implements authenticated routes, storing/displaying user generated content and custom react hooks and etc.

React, Firebase (Auth, Firestore, Storage)

Design Agency (Landing page)

Fun landing page for virtual design agency. I used GSAP for creating the animation. I focused on understanding creating the usable components and how to effectively develop UI for better use experience.

React, GSAP

Work Experience

Pig's Ear Restaurant, Dublin 2, Ireland Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Floor staff - worked in an enthusiastic and dynamic work environment providing a professional customer service for high quality dining experience

Kitchen & Table Restaurant, Clarion Hotel, Stockholm Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Floor staff - I was nominated as a team leader during my time in Kitchen & Table. I mainly involved in setting the target sales on daily basis, supervising team members, communicated directly to manger and was responsible for the shift

Education

Technological University Dublin

BA (Hons) Commercial Modern Music (BIMM) - Songwriting Graduating May 2021

Udemy

Web Development Bootcamp

Cit a Web Developer Job: Mastering the Modern Workflow

2018 - 2018

2018 - 2018

Achievement

Class President

Selected as a class president in High School for two year duration. I delivered an effective communication skills leading the class, finding and resolving problem to assist students with their school experience.